emmi@emmi.dev | denver, co | emmi.dev

SUMMARY

I'm Emmi, an experienced full-stack developer that loves clean, communicative code and taking care of the little things to delight users while maintaining big picture ideas. I'm passionate about type systems, testing, intuitive UI/UX, accessibility, and upleveling fellow developers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Current stack: TypeScript/JavaScript, React, HTML + CSS/SCSS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Git **Exposure to:** ¡Query, C, Python, Java, R, SML, Google Cloud Platform

EDUCATION

The University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

June 2018

B.S. - Computer Science, B.A. - Psychology with honors

EXPERIENCE

Brandfolder, Denver, CO

Full Stack Software Developer Senior Software Engineer I

November 2019 - April 2021 April 2021 - Present

- + Organized work, reviewed and contributed code to lead teams of 2-7 software engineers to build and update features core to Brandfolder's offerings. For example, rebuilt the jQuery + slim asset information editing UI to use API-powered React, created a collaborative work management space for in-progress assets, and expanded taxonomy capabilities by supporting multi-value custom fields and automation
- + Introduced TypeScript to the codebase, significantly improving code quality, durability, and maintainability
- Collaborated closely with Product and Customer Experience team members to resolve customer issues weekly
- + Mentored junior developers and supported coworkers in areas of passions like TypeScript, testing, and accessibility best practices

Microsoft, Redmond, WA

Software Engineer I

August 2018 - November 2019

- + Developed reporting features across Microsoft's Azure DevOps product by writing and reviewing code as a member of one of its only horizontal teams
- + Collaborated closely with product managers and other engineers from start to finish on features including spec reviews, development design, development, and post-deployment telemetry to measure success and adoption
- + Contributed to a performance effort that resulted in a 50% Apdex improvement in the team's main feature area
- Served as feature lead for displaying work rollup progress on Azure DevOps backlogs
- + Monitored live site health, managed and tuned automated alerts, facilitated daily stand-up, and worked to resolve bugs and customer issues during on-call engineer rotations

Square, San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer Intern - Developer Platform

June - September 2017

Google

Engineering Practicum Intern - Cloud Marketplace June - September 2016 Engineering Practicum Intern - Knowledge Panel UI

June - September 2015